<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Tomodachi94's Musings</title><link>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Tomodachi94's Musings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Tomodachi94. All Rights Reserved unless explicitly stated.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:57:13 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up a development environment with Neovim and ComputerCraft</title><link>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/computercraft-neovim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:57:13 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/computercraft-neovim/</guid><description>ComputerCraft is a Minecraft mod that adds programmable computers to the game. These computers are programmed with Lua, a scripting language written in C.
Neovim is a fork of the Vim text editor; it adds configuration with Lua and language server support, among other things, to the classic Vim editor.
In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking you through setting up a tolerable IDE-like environment for ComputerCraft in Neovim, similar to Visual Studio Code&amp;rsquo;s IntelliSense.</description></item><item><title>Nix quickstart guide</title><link>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/nix-quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/nix-quickstart/</guid><description>This guide helps you start quickly with using Nix as a package manager. This guide covers setting up, nix-shell, nix-env -iA, and Home Manager.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick way to get started with using Nix as a package manager without diving into the complex internals:
Install Nix with sh &amp;lt;(curl -L https://nixos.org/nix/install) --daemon. Make sure to add that snippet at the end to your shell configuration or you&amp;rsquo;ll have some trouble later.</description></item><item><title>Editing Fandom wikis with Neovim</title><link>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/fandom-neovim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/fandom-neovim/</guid><description>This guide assumes you know how to insert text, move the cursor, and execute commands in Neovim.
Neovim is a text editor based on Vim. It is extremely extensible, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking advantage of that to edit on Fandom wikis.
Install Neovim (but Vim should also work for this guide). It might already be on your Linux computer. You will also need an installation of Python, and a library called mwclient from pip, as well as a plugin manager.</description></item><item><title>How I Transcribe Handwritten Notes Into Obsidian</title><link>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/handwritten-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomodachi94.github.io/blog/handwritten-notes/</guid><description>Obsidian is a Markdown-based note taking tool focused on connections between notes. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how I transcribe my handwritten Cornell notes into a linkable web of thought.
Related: Why You Should Take Notes By Hand
Image courtesy of Icez~enwikibooks at English Wikibooks, Public domain, via Wikimedia Commons
I first begin by creating a scratch note, similar to a map of content (MOC). It&amp;rsquo;s temporary, but it can be evolved into a MOC if you want, or just deleted when done.</description></item></channel></rss>